Conor Desmond

P: 518-469-0921 | Email: conordesmond28@yahoo.com

Accomplished programming professional, who specialized in sports-related predictive analytics with DataRobot. Recognized for team building and team motivation and can predict complex outcomes. A driven, self-starter who is adept at relationship building, programming, and providing results.

Key strengths:

Operations

Analytics Scouting Perseverance

Data Modeling

Honesty

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

REGENERON PHARMACEUTICALS - East Greenbush, NY

May 2023 - August 2023

Intern, Process Sciences

- Added to an existing Excel template for a unified data hierarchy using the current data hierarchy configurations.
- Designed graphs based on the hierarchy template, led focus groups, designed a poster for my project; presented on my project in front of my department.

SOCIAL MEDIA POSTS

October 2022 - Present

X (Formerly Twitter) Predictions

- Before the playoffs began, using my predictive data models built in DataRobot, predicted the 2022 MLB World Series winner, 2023 NBA finals winner, all 2023 NBA first round winners; 2023 Super Bowl teams.
- Before the playoffs, predicted the 2024 CFP championship teams and winner from my models built using tensorflow and scikit-learn.
- Before 2024 Super Bowl, predicted Chiefs to win Super Bowl by 3 points.
- My predicted RA/GM in the 2022 MLB playoffs for the Astros and Phillies were only off .06 runs.
- Check the pinned thread from my X account for evidence: @conord282 and my GitHub for code: ConorD28

CERTIFICATES / SKILLS

- Baseball Analytics, Scoutables Certificate, Sports Management Worldwide, 2023
 - Training included: sabermetrics, role of analytics in MLB, advanced baseball statistics, data-driven advanced scouting, and in-game preparation, how to capture & analyze baseball data. (Mentored by Scoutables Founder, Ari Kaplan). References: Dr. Lynn Lashbrook, President, Sports Management Worldwide, 503-445-7105. Ari Kaplan, kaplanball@gmail.com
- Rapsodo Pitching Certificate. Jun 2023
- Skills: R, SQL, Java, Python, novice C++, SPSS Modeler, Excel; intermediate Spanish

EDUCATION

Marist College - Poughkeepsie, NY

August 2020 - May 2024

- B.S. in Data Science and Analytics with minor in Mathematics
- **GPA**: 3.7

AWARDS / AFFILIATIONS

- Analyst (Synergy), Baseball Committee part of Marist's Sports Analytics Club 2022 and 2023
- Dean's List, Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY
- National Society of Leadership and Success 2021 Present
- DataFest Participant, Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY 2022 and 2023
- Emerging Leaders Program 2020 2021
- Academy Certificate of Achievement, Uncommon Sports Group, Minneapolis, MN 2022
- Marist Analytics Community 2021 2023
- Triple C Award, Shaker High School, Latham, NY Jun 2020
 - Given to a member of my high school's senior class who demonstrated the qualities of courage, character, and commitment.